Okay, this is the spec driven
development workshop. Um, if you're not
here for spec driven, you're probably
here for one of two other sessions which
is the landing. Um, just very very
briefly before we jump in, you know, I'm
going to talk about the survey again. Uh
please if you haven't already uh given
ratings for other sessions and so forth
uh please do go to aonativedev.co/servey
uh and you can fill in uh the details
there. Um and that QR code goes straight
to it as well. Uh a little bit about
what we're going to be talking about
today. My name is Simon Maple. I I head
up Devril here at Tessle. Uh my
colleague here, Mr. Alan Pope.
>> Hello. That's me.
>> Do you want to introduce yourself, Alan?
Uh yeah, I'm Alan. I work with Simon at
Tesla.
>> Awesome. And and yeah, today we're going
to be talking a little bit about spec
driven. Why spec driven? First of all,
what are the some of the challenges uh
it can it can help us with in and around
uh AI development uh through various
agents and other tools that we use. Um
so when we think about how you know we
talk about AI agents, we probably should
really classify that a little bit. First
of all, I guess for for many their first
experiences in around AI coding or
assistance for AI coding was was
probably something like chat GPT. I'm
sure we're all here. How many years ago?
Three years ago now.
>> Something crazy.
>> When was 35? Was that three years ago?
>> It's bizarre, isn't it? Three years ago.
So yeah, we probably typed in, can you
write some code that does this? We copy
pasted it to our IDE. It broke. So we
grabbed the exception, we threw it back
into chat GPT, it worked out. Typically
we would get to a solution, but the UI,
the UX is is is pretty awful because
we're copyping the twin. So then
something like Copilot came out and this
was really my my first experience at
real uh AI assisted development in in my
place, my home, my my IDE. So
essentially, yeah, whether it's tab
completion, whether you're asking it to
do more complex things, uh it would go
ahead and do that. And of course uh
there are more agentic style things that
uh that copilot will do these days but
it's the more assisted part of copilot
which I started uh I started building
out and then we kind of fell into the
world of AI agents and I guess one of
the big questions is what's the
difference between an AI agent and an AI
assistant. Well an AI assistant is
typically something that that that that
does these smaller tasks. It's much more
conversational. We we think about it in
a more chatbased uh environment. I ask
it something gives me a response. I
think about it. I validate it. I give it
another question. You're not actually
just sending something off to an agent
that goes away and builds this whole
thing, makes decisions for itself, maybe
uses other agents or sub agents, goes
and uses third party services. It's the
longer running, more complex uh
definition of a of what an agent is. Um,
but agents do have pitfalls. Uh, no
agent is perfect. And these are some of
the pitfalls when we're not using
specifications in our agentic
development. Um, I did ask ChatGpt to
create these uh these images. It was a
very self-reflective moment for ChatGpt.
One of them, the first issue that chat
GPT thought it had was something called
collateral damage. And and essentially
this is when, and I'm sure everyone's
experienced this when Vive coding, I've
been sending loads of prompts to
whatever I want to work with, whether
it's Claude or whether it's um, you
know, codeex or whatever. and my 100th
on my 100th prompt, uh, it goes ahead
and actually then says, "Yes, I'll fix
this for you." But it actually breaks
something else. Uh, and it's the
classic, well, I've I've made this work
and that's what you asked for, but I've
broken something else. This is what we
call a collateral damage where it
doesn't have to be an exception or it
doesn't have to be an error. It could be
a behavioral thing, but it but it
affects another piece. Another piece is
when I'll get to that 100th prompt,
actually, the first 10, is that still in
its context? has that been has that been
you know removed when it actually
compacted its uh its backlog of all my
of all my prompts sometimes it forgets
some of the instructions and that's
because when we prompt prompts are
throwaway artifacts they're throwaway
messages it's just chat um and so as a
result it's AI will agents will find it
hard to to to keep track to to hold all
of these uh this string of requests
through
uh another example of how agents can
sometimes fail is hallucinations and we
all what hallucinations are. Um, and
very often when we think about coding,
it it very frequently manifests itself
as a hallucination to a to an API that
we thought existed, but actually it
doesn't exist. Um, sometimes it's a real
hallucination. Sometimes it's actually
version blur where the training data is
actually training across a huge number
of different versions and it's the agent
isn't necessarily fully understanding
what version I am actually coding
against and it's actually trying to hit
a different version of that correct
library uh the API on that and of course
maybe something's been deprecated or
removed maybe something just hasn't
reached the version that I'm using yet
and it's trying to invoke that. So, this
is kind of like a version blur where the
agent's training isn't taking into
account the actual version. Uh, I'm
using
uh stale training data. I'm I'm really
sad about this. This poor little guy.
He's uh he's had his hand removed. Chat
GPT wasn't wasn't having it with
training data. But, uh, Spring version
7, our wonderful friends at Spring. In
fact, one of them is Josh Long. If you
don't know Josh Long, um, incredible uh,
Java advocate and and Spring advocate.
He's actually in the other room, but
don't go. He's he's his his wonderful
talk will also be on uh recorded but
let's say spring version 7 comes out
this month which it is there's nothing
in the training data of course for
spring version 7 because the trading
data was actually if you look at claude
uh created in January of this year so
there's no way other than the LLM
looking at the either trying to find
some docs or looking at uh the actual
code uh in the in the repository in its
uh in its dependency that it's
downloaded to actually try and code
against that. So, how does it how does
it, you know, work with either massive
legacy or very new things that are just
outside of its training data.
Um, yeah, lack of persistent knowledge.
So, very often if I'm in a session, if I
create a session and I get it just
right, I'm I'm giving it the the right
detail about how I want it to code for
me, my best practices, I want you to
write these tests when I do this, etc.,
etc. As soon as that session goes and
dies, I have to recreate that every
single time because it doesn't exist.
And finally,
everyone's got the t-shirts. Yeah, if
you haven't got one of our uh t-shirts,
it just says you're absolutely right on
it. When it does error, you get this
wonderful message. You're absolutely
right. And this is actually I was
thinking the other day we should
probably write a little bot that goes
through your clawed history and works
out how many what's the your absolutely
rights per minute or per per hour you're
getting just the the sheer frustration
oral loops that we get. Um and it of
course does that once and then gets the
answer perfectly right. Right. Or does
it go again and again and again and we
hit this spiral of you're absolutely
right until we get very very frustrated
and then we realize well actually we're
not giving it any more information.
It's got the same amount of information
unless it tries to do a web search or
something. So, it's very hard for it
with the same amount of information to
try and try and get a correct answer.
We're actually relying on the
nondeterminism to hope it finds finds is
lucky to find some other answer. So, how
do we avoid that? How do we make agents
more accurate? Um, more predictable,
more using more current data with
validation, but also less frustrating so
that it's, you know, we're not
constantly going through these spirals
or these loops trying to get it to to do
the right thing. And at Tesla certainly
and of course at AI Native Dev, we
believe the answer to that is
specifications. And all those issues
that I just mentioned before,
specifications are actually a great way
to be able to think about a solution to
that. Whether it's just huge numbers of
prompts, well, put them in a
specification. If it's version blur,
well, you know, create a specification
that describes my stack or describes
what I am downloading and and how I can
use that and so forth. And there's a
couple of ways that at Tesla we've
thought about this and I'll I'll I'll
cover those. And it really leads into
our kind of like longer term vision as
to how specifications can change the way
we as software developers uh build
software. and and the longer term vision
is um where we write specifications as a
definition for an application. So if you
imagine an app spec where that spec
defines the capabilities of the
application and capabilities are really
just another way of describing tests. If
I say I want you to do this, it's
equivalent of essentially saying I'm
going to write a bunch of test cases
that prove you do that. So a set of a
set of uh
um capabilities or tests also a
directive or a direction of how an API
should be built and so forth. These
these things it's just a markdown file.
We could kind of like describe it as we
wish. The other way of course is
building specifications that help guide
an agent to build code. So my first one
was very specentric. In other words, I'm
building a spec that's the center of my
universe. build me an app from it. When
we think about specs as guidance, we're
talking about can I build a set of
specifications that when I use my agent,
it can use those specifications as
context to guide the agent to build in a
specific way. That could be anything
from what we're calling kind of like
these usage tiles within Tessle whereby
in this case maybe I'm using React
version, I don't know, 191 or something
like that, a fairly new one. This would
contain usage information about how my
LLM should use this library. And this
can continue into maybe it's guidance
around how my organization sets out its
security policy or ways in which I want
you to use TypeScript and ways in which
I don't want you to use TypeScript, my
your coding best practices and so forth.
So, there's a bunch of specifications
that provide guidance or steering uh to
uh applications. And during this
hands-on workshop, we're going to go
through a bunch of that and and I I'll
give you a very very brief demo of of uh
of Tessle, which will actually show you
the the the power in which using these
specifications we can guide those agents
and then I'll pass over to Alan. Um, oh
actually let me jump through that and
then I'll pass over to Alan who will uh
talk you through what we're going to do
in this workshop to actually collaborate
with specification writing and then
building [clears throat] an application
that then uses that specification. And
one of the core things is we're going to
do uh a we're going to do collaboration
because we're going to be uploading a
lot of these specifications into a
repository that we can then share from.
So if this gentleman writes a
specification and that lady over there
wants to use that, we don't want to
build their own specifications, use it
in isolation and never share because if
you're part of the same organization,
you'll have a lot of the same policies.
So we want one person to upload, another
person to use or a platform team to
suggest and propose a number of uh a
number of specifications that an entire
organization or team can pull down and
use so that we're guiding agents uh very
predictably.
Okay. So, um, a couple of things I'm
going to show you. First of all, um,
I've already downloaded Tessle. Um, some
of this will be in the workshop. If you
wanted to follow along a little bit,
you're absolutely welcome to. Um, what I
have already done is an npm install
minusg at tessle/ cli. What this is
going to do is it's going to globally
install the Tesla CLI onto my local
environment so that wherever I am, I can
just run Tessle and life is good. If you
run that uh I will run Tessle version,
you should get something along the lines
of a 050 version. Now I have that I
actually have
a nice little CLI where I can do certain
things. I think I'm uh I think I'm
logged in. So let me quickly Tessle log
out
and Tessle log. If I do tessle who am I
right now, you'll see that I'm not
logged in. This is probably a little bit
low. Sorry. Uh you can see I'm not
currently logged in. So I'm going to run
Tesla login. That's going to send me to
a new window. Uh if you don't have an
account, you'll need to go through a
number of steps. You can create a free
account just by either using your your
Gmail or your uh or your Google account
rather or or your GitHub account. Um,
I'm just going to confirm that that is
indeed
the code over here. It logs me in. There
we go. And from this point on, I can
actually do a bunch of workspace,
private workspace creation, of course.
Uh, within where are we? Within Tessle,
I thought
uh uh maybe it's in here. uh within uh
there we go at Tesla we have a public
registry and this is a registry in which
we at Tesla can publish a whole bunch of
tiles and these tiles can be used by
everyone in their general development.
So far what we have uh published are
these usage tiles and they are
descriptions of open- source code and
what that means is if you were to pull
those descriptions down of open source
code uh those descriptions will allow
they will be provided to an agent so
that agent knows how to use that open
source at that version correctly. I'm
going to give you a very brief demo of
that. Uh but first if I was just to
search this registry and search it for I
don't know I mentioned spring right? If
I was to search here for spring, you'll
see a number of different kind of like
Maven Spring uh um uh kind of usage
tiles. And each of these has a huge
amount of information about how an agent
with examples with coding examples how
an agent should use uh this library. Um
so what I'm going to do is if I go uh if
I run Tesla in it, what this is going to
do is it's going to try and it's going
to it's going to set up my environment.
It's going to try and download uh any
usage tiles that I require. Um and it's
going to in this case uh it's created
two oh it's saying two agents need setup
and it's created an MCP client for both
claude code and cursor because it
recognizes I have that on my local
environment. Now when I run claude the
MCP server is there. So I shall say use
that. And if I run MCP here, you'll see
that Tesla exists and I have a bunch of
tools such as install and search. And
these are looking for these usage specs
and trying to install them. And what
installation means is is once it's found
a usage spec, one of these uh markdown
descriptors, it's going to pull that
down so that I have context local in my
file system that I can then have my
agents use. Uh it's not something I
check in. I would check in a like a
similar to a package JSON but it will be
a tessle JSON and that Tessle JSON file
will describe which usage tiles I need
to download when I simply do a Tessle
install. So at this stage what I could
do is um maybe I'll say something along
the lines of create an application
uh that sums a set of dice or die
[snorts] uh use uh use dice notation
notation as input
uh code uh or create typescript
and use the Tessle MCP server to get
usage
tiles. Um, I could also say something
like use the commander if I was really
interested. It might do this anyway. Use
the commander uh CLI uh dependency.
Um, so now you can see straight away
it's it's trying to do a search. It's
it's trying to pull down some some
TypeScript. um usage tiles. Um it's now
looking for a CLI. It's probably not
going to find much there. Uh but it
should do a search for commander. So now
it's going to pull down the commander um
the commander tile and so forth. And
once it has that, it's going to do a
really important step when it tries to
create uh it's trying to do an install
of that. That uh will probably work. Um
actually, I'll just say yes to all. Uh,
and once it does that installation,
there's a really important step which is
when it tries to next build something,
it's going to it's going to essentially
try and identify what the context is
from all of these usage tiles because if
you think about the sheer amount of
usage tiles and data that we're going to
have, we don't want to flood the uh we
don't want to flood the environment with
those usage tiles. We only want to use a
certain amount of them. So what it tends
to do is it tends to try and identify
based on the request which parts in a
sub agent this is which parts of the
usage data it or the context it it needs
to to satisfy that request. It will pull
them take that pass that back to the
main agent and it will use that as part
of that that creation.
So that's I'll I'll I'll leave that just
for a second u in the in the interest of
time. But what I also want to show you
is something which uh I kind of like
mentioned these steering tiles. What
I've shown here is how we use how we use
these these um uh markdown usage tiles
to essentially describe how an agent
should use open source uh code. But if I
want if I had private code, if I had
private libraries, so nothing open
source, or if I just wanted to tell an
agent, this is how I want you to work. I
want to steer it in a way that my
organization works. I want to be able to
create my own usage tiles, my own
context, upload that and allow agents to
use that. So I want to show you that
here as well. If I run something like uh
Tessle uh work
spaces, no workspace
um here a workspace, I can create my own
private workspaces. Uh I have a number
of things I can do. I can create some
list etc. So I'm going to say list my
workspaces. Uh this is the one that
we're going to use in this workshop, the
AIND workshop. So if I say um Tessle
workspace uh actually no what I will
rather than that do is I'm going to just
quickly show you what I have in this uh
in this directory. I have something
called an index MD. And let me actually
take you to
VS Code somewhere. Where's VS Code?
there. Thank you. This is my index MD.
Uh this is the core root of where my uh
of where Tessle and the agent will look
for uh information for a specific tile.
In this case, this is my TypeScript
style guide. So I want to provide the
agent information about how I want it to
write TypeScript based on my
organization's best practices. In here,
I can link to other files. So I can say
this is how I want you to do um testing.
And in here I can say what good looks
like, what bad looks like, etc. And so
as my agent build tests, it grabs the
necessary context, pulls it into the
main agent and builds the tests as I
want. Perhaps I want to do a code
review. If I do a code review, it will
look at my style guide and give me input
or give me uh a set of suggestions based
on my style guide. I don't want a
generic output. I want something
specific to my organization. So, how do
I actually how do I actually use this as
uh gosh, where am I? How do I use this
as part of my environment? Well, what I
would do is um if I do a quick uh vi of
my tile.json,
this is an example of what I would need
to actually publish to a workspace. And
here I can say, what was the name of it?
It was a d workshop.
Thank you.
uh dear workshop. I'm going to create a
tile which is called /typescript. I'll
make this version uh 0.0.1.
Whoops.
There we go. Typescript style guides
blah blah blah. There's a bunch of
steering tiles there. I'll save that.
Oops.
I'll save that. Now, what I need to do
is I just need to publish this. So I
will just go tessle tile publish and
then I will just put space dot dot is
just the path to where my tesla to where
my uh tile.json is. Soon as I do that it
publishes it directly to that ad
workshop. And if I was to now go back to
uh my
here, if I was to come back here and go
to the registry, I can have a look at my
account and I'll say go to my aimed
workshop and I now have a tile. And this
is a tile that I can use simply by going
to somewhere like um Claude
and saying
uh let's say no
uh actually let's just do an npm
install. I can say something like um
install the tessle yes whatever install
the tessle tile uh what do we call it a
workshop slash type
right I'm just going to say yes to all
stop bothering me uh type they're like
children aren't they agents uh type
script okay uh now when it installs this
it's going to pull that locally to my
project it's going to add it to my
tesslej JSON which is a description of
all the tiles and steering I I I want to
I want to add uh that's where it's doing
the install now and then as soon as I
say something like now you know uh
perform a code review
review if I do something like that it's
now going to use that as part of my best
practices and so I'm using context I'm
using knowledge based on my organization
or based on the the way I want something
to be built uh in order in order to um
to do what I want to do.
So, um I think I'll pause there. I've
only been like six hours right in this
2-hour workshop. I'll pause there and
I'll um and actually no, I won't pause
there. What it's doing is you can see
it's reading a whole bunch of now from
the uh from my usage tiles as part of
that code review. And if I was to just
hit control O, you'll see it's actually
looking at various issues to fix. And a
lot of these, or in fact, pretty much
all of these are going to be direct um
directly from what I what my steering
pile, my steering a my steering
information knowledge, uh will describe
what I want and what I don't want. Um
and there we go. a whole bunch of
information uh based on based on how
what what Claude Code has created
differs from my my coding best
practices. I really will stop there now
and I'll pass over to uh to Alan. Any
questions while Alan is setting up?
>> Yes. Uh
Yeah, great question. So the question
was does does Tesla tiles work uh with
or against the claude MD? Actually when
we do the Tesla in it, one of the first
things we do is actually add to the
claude MD file. So we are we are
encouraging Claude through its means to
use Tessle. Uh there will be other
things that we will integrate with like
tessle like claude skills and things
like that is you know also another
amazing way that that can be done. So we
want to integrate with those more native
uh uh kind of integrations so that
Tessle can be best used with that. One
of one of the the key things is we're
not restricted to any agent. So anything
that uses MTP you can use Tessle. So if
you're using clawed code, someone else
over here is using Gemini, someone else
over there is using codeex, you know,
you can use the same knowledge across
all and we'll just try and plug in at at
the right stages. Um we'll take
questions in a bit as again I'll pass
over to Alan. Hello everyone. Uh me
again. Uh so I wanted to do a little
workshop with you and give you some uh
capacity to be creative and come up with
something yourself. Um so not many
constraints on what um what I'll ask you
to do. Um and the concept is wrapped. So
I'm sure you've all heard of Spotify
wrapped. uh where around about this time
of year, everyone gets told what
terrible music taste they have. Uh I
know I do. This is actually mine.
Michael Boué appears in my Spotify list
because the Alexa in the kitchen is tied
to my Spotify account and my wife likes
Michael Boué. Honest. Uh that's my story
and I'm sticking to it. Uh so what uh
this does is generally take a load of
data and then summarize it in a visually
pleasant way that you're probably
inclined to want to share with your
friends or maybe not in my case. And so
uh over here what I've uh suggested is
you create a wrapped of some kind. Sorry
about that just now. Sorry. Uh a wrapped
of some kind. Now, I'll give you some
inspiration in a minute, but that's the
goal is to create some kind of wrapped
of this year because it's about that
time.
Here's some guidelines. Pick something
meaningful to you. Uh what that is, I
don't know. Everyone has a different
definition of what meaningful is. Uh
write some guidance in markdown format
and build a beautiful dashboard. Now, I
think you know, beauty is subjective.
The last time we did this in uh in our
office in London, we had a room full of
students and boy oh boy, their
definition of beautiful is very
different from mine. Um I think the key
word that they used to give beauty was
brain rot. Uh if you feel the need to
put brain rot in your definition, then
uh you'll find an interesting uh result.
Uh and then maybe draw some conclusions
from this. Maybe it'll pull together
some data and teach you something you
didn't know. like I didn't know that I
liked Michael Boué. Um, and then maybe
share your creations. We've got a git
repo. If you want to, you can fork that
and I'll walk you through what to do
there. Uh, or if you if you create
something really crazy, you want to come
up here and show the world, then uh,
you're more than welcome to do it. But
if you want to keep it to yourself, I
completely understand. No judgment.
Here's some suggestions. Uh, GitHub
wrapped. Uh, I'll show you an example of
that. like what did I do this year on
GitHub or maybe GitLab or some other
code hosting solution doesn't have to be
GitHub could be anything that you can
get data out of email wrapped this is a
possibly dangerous one like get an AI to
scrape through all of your email and
tell you how angry you are on certain
days of the week or you know interpret
the the people that you communicate with
in a particular way that might be fun
wrapped if you're a Straa user or
whatever fit people do. Uh you could
maybe get some data from that and
process that or maybe even rather meta,
you could do Claude unwrapped or
whatever agent you use, get the logs of
your conversations and see if you can
introspect that and come up with a
dashboard that tells you, you know,
what's your favorite word that you use
all the time. I think it might be
awesome if we were to ask Claude. Um oh,
browser history wrapped. I did this one.
This is quite fun. You can see uh what
uh you know websites you go to a lot.
You may not want to share that one.
That's entirely up to you. Again, no
judgment. Um I did do this uh on my work
laptop and it was all perfectly fine. So
that's not a problem. I'm not going to
show it to you. Uh but that's just some
ideas. You might have other things. Uh
some examples that came up at hackathon
we had in London. Uh, one person
accessed their like their Costco card to
see their Costco history and see what
they've been buying for the year, but in
fact they access their girlfriend's
Costco card data in order to see. I'm
not suggesting you do anything illegal.
I would like to come back to America
again sometime. Um, other things you
might do is uh interrogate your Netflix
history or maybe if you're a big
self-hoster, you could look at your Plex
history or jellyfin or whatever it is
that you've got data that you can
access. Pull that data in and then uh
build a dashboard. Could be fun.
Here's an example that I made which is
going to be terrible. Uh, I asked for a
GitHub dashboard. Um, actually I don't
need that slide, right? Uh, this is my
year in GitHub. And you'll notice it
looks terrible. Uh, and uh, that's, you
know, that's an aesthetic I quite like,
the green neon. Not quite this much, but
okay. But and it's not it's not quite
what I was after. I didn't steer it very
well. This was very much vibecoded like
from nothing. Um, yeah, total events,
how many pull requests, you know, it
doesn't really look like a Spotify
wrapped, uh, top languages. I've never
written any GDScript in my life. I don't
know where it got that from. Um, yeah,
some of these other things are vaguely
interesting. You know, how many pushes,
how many pulls, you know, how much
activity. I went a bit crazy this month.
Um, not so much in other months. So, you
know, you can you can create something
very quickly um, and it might not look
great. and I did this in like 10
minutes. So, I would challenge you to
spend more than 10 minutes. And your
challenge is to make something that
looks better than this. And I don't
think it's that hard. Um, so how did I
go about doing this? Well, um, I just
used uh Claude and created a really
basic prompt. I didn't use any of the
the new skills that, uh, Simon talks
about with Tessle and I didn't write a
comprehensive spec. Normally I do. I did
this really really basic, right? So, all
I did was I installed Tessle so that
Claude was aware of it. Uh, and I made
sure I had the latest version and uh Oh,
that's nice. Um, and I'll show you the
prompt that I came up with, right?
Hopefully, you can read this. It's
pretty big. Um, so I said we're working
on example for a workshop. Make it
quickly safety. Hit the goal. I'm only
going to run it on my laptop. It's not
going to run in production. Don't worry
about it. The main goal create a your
your year in GitHub summarizing personal
activity over the last year. It's 2025.
I had to say it's 2025 because on one
occasion doing this it thought it was
2024 and went and found all my history
for 2024. I was like that's pretty
useless. Some sub goals uh make a usable
example for all of you. That was one of
the sub goals. Um and contribute
reusable tiles to the Tesla spec
registry. I just threw that in there
hoping it would uh come up with
something. And I asked it to do this in
two stages. And this is really what you
will probably want to do uh if you're
going to partake in this uh this fund is
create a data gathering process that
gets all the data via some method uh and
puts it somewhere. And then the second
part is to create a web page that like
shows that off in a beautiful way. I
think what did I say? I said something
about did I say somewhere in here mono?
Oh yeah, mono font with green
highlights. I think it took that a
little bit too seriously there. Yeah,
there we go. Anyway, uh what did that
look like? Um somewhere here I've got
the entire claude conversation. If you
want, we could go through this, but I
don't think that's a good use of
anyone's time. But it literally was me
just asking that that question. I pasted
that prompt in and it asked a few
questions. It went looking around the
directory structure, made a folder to
put my data in, [snorts] uh created a
git ignore file, and it did a few other
things like created a node uh JavaScript
thing to go and fetch my GitHub data.
And then it went off and created some
sample data as well so that it could
test the front end. But I didn't really
have to do any uh interaction with this.
This is real proper VI coding nonsense.
um inserted 2025 in there. Brilliant. Uh
and so yeah, it's it did it right at the
end what I got was um a file, a data
file which contains my contributions
popy on GitHub. That's me. Um and uh
like pulled out that's contributions to
this very repository and all the other
stuff is down there somewhere, you know,
lots and lots and lots and lots of
contributions. Um, and somewhere, uh,
was that everything? Um,
uh, somewhere in here, I've got all of
that. I called it year in GitHub. I've
got a dodgy internet connection here,
but this is all the stuff that it
created. Now, it did have a go at
creating some tiles. I I don't think it
was especially uh effective, but it
wanted to create a couple of tiles. one
for the GitHub data fetcher and one for
the visualizer. Um, I will put all of
this in the Git repo that I'll show you
in just a minute. And you can clone that
and use that as a base if you want to. I
won't put my personal data in there and
I strongly recommend if you put any of
this on GitHub, you don't put your
personal data in there, but you know,
uh, you do you, as they say. Um,
[snorts] the repo is here. It's AI
native dev community on GitHub. Um, and
we've called it AI ND workshops. And
there's a folder here, Devcon 25NYC,
that just has some notes and suggestions
for what you might want to do. Um, and
what I would do is fork that repo and
press the star button so you can join
the lonely two people, me and one other
person who start
quite sad, isn't it? Uh, and get this
rocketing up to trending on GitHub, I
don't think. Um, and then start building
something. We could have a go at doing
it live on either your or my laptop if
we get an internet connection. But
that's that's really all I went through.
And it actually turned out I created
something. It doesn't look visually
super compelling, but I could iterate on
that. It didn't use Tesla tiles, but I
didn't coersse it very much. You'll see
I barely mentioned Tesla at all. I
didn't create a comprehensive spec. So
what I what I'm trying to show you is
don't do what I did. Like there are
better ways to do it. This kind of
illustrates some of the points that
Simon was making earlier that it you
know it it takes what you give it and if
you don't give it comprehensive
instructions then you know you get
monochrome neon green nonsense in the
web page. That's the answer. Um if you
have any questions I think that was the
only other slide was uh if you have any
questions uh feel free to shout and
we'll throw a microphone in your
direction. uh but I would love to help
you create a dashboard looking back over
uh either using Tesla or contributing to
Tesla uh using uh our [snorts] uh spec
registry. Any questions at all? Any
comments?
Any comments about my wonderful taste in
monochrome web pages?
>> Yeah.
>> Or music?
>> Pardon?
>> Or Ah, yes. No, I can't. That's not me.
Uh right. Uh where do we go? Okay, so
next steps if you wanted to go back to
GitHub perhaps.
>> Okay, so the next steps uh this will
contain kind of a little bit step by
step in terms
>> Yeah, I should show that actually
>> in in terms of what you need to do. So
>> it tells you what to do.
>> It tells you what to do. Perfect. So if
you go to GitHub AI native dev community
with hyphens
um you'll see the AI and D workshops
there. You can start that if you wish
but um or or fork it if you wish. Then
from there in the Devcon 25NYC folder,
there is a readme there with
instructions that will walk you through
how to do things like whether it's
creating a Tesla account or uh looking
at what a what uh what specs that you
want to want to build. It's entirely up
to you how you want to coers or guide
your agent. Feel free to either use
Tessle specs that we have around uh open
source libraries if you wish to use
those or feel free to add guidance as um
as markdown. This could be maybe you're
already using cursor rules or maybe
you're using other um uh other steering
style specs to make sure agents do what
you want. Add them as specifications
into the into the workshop. Uh and if
you want to contribute that back or use
what other people in the workshop are
doing if you can send us your ID on the
where are we saying the discord is it?
>> Uh yeah or just come and show us. Uh I
open it here somewhere. Uh uh where have
I lost it?
>> Wow that's bright.
>> Yeah. Sorry. I I realized that dark mode
is not great for uh
>> Yeah.
But much better [laughter] actually for
your eyes. So yeah. Uh did you show the
workspaces?
>> Uh I didn't actually. No. So you saw I
created No, I didn't create a private
workspace. I I was a me I was added
previously about 30 minutes ago. No, an
hour ago to this workspace. When you
create your Tesla account, if you do
Tesla who am I at the command line, uh
you will you will find yourself with a
wonderful user ID called user_bd
blah blah blah. If you go to tesl.io/
io/acounts.
Uh you will be able to There we go. Uh
so username here is Popey. Uh that's
because you've changed your username to
something nice. Uh if you go to
tesla.io/acounts
uh and you and you log in, you'll be
able to change your ID to whatever you
wish. Or you could use user whatever
whatever whatever. So if you go account
settings down here, u you can see Alan
can change his username there to
whatever he wishes. If you then share
that with us, we'll add you to the
workspace and then you can see
everything there including including
that TypeScript um including that
TypeScript tile I just added and feel
you have you will have rights to publish
uh as well as download anyone else's
tiles. So I would say start there maybe
let's spend about 20 to 30 minutes
building the specifications you want
having a look at specifications that you
can pull down from the Tessle registry.
Uh and then from there we'll publish
those, we will share those and then we
can start building the app hopefully
using the guidance uh from these tiles.
Does that make sense?
Any questions? Any any anyone stuck and
everyone know what your next steps are?
Hands up if you're
which way should we go? Hands up. Let's
try and wake people up. Hands up if you
know what you're doing.
>> Ah, [laughter]
>> we have seven people who know what
they're doing. Cool. Tell a friend. Um I
think [laughter]
>> you can you can collaborate with the
person next to you if uh you know you
want to uh work together and use
multiple brain cells in order to uh
collaborate on this thing. That works
>> and Alan and I will uh we'll wander
around if there's uh
>> y
>> or you I I could live vibe the you know
you direct me through it and
>> I can do it. Let's let's let the room do
it for a little bit and then we'll
perhaps jump into that once we have in
fact maybe maybe maybe people can build
specifications and then you can use some
of those specifications to uh uh to to
to build that.
>> Awesome. Okay, we'll give 20 minutes or
so 25 minutes um start building the the
the the markdown that you want. Anyone
has any questions throw a hand up and
we'll we'll come by. I'll stop. Sweet.
Sorry. The installation command for
Tesla is npm install-g
uh at
uh tessleward
slash cli.
make it embedded
my product, you saw that it was like
super brief. Uh, and I'm I'm quite a
wordy kind of guy. And this is one of
the reasons why this whole spectrum
development works in my head is because
I find it really convenient to be
incredibly devo verbose about what I
want to create. And so if if you can get
into that mindset of you're explaining
to a an alien or a three-year-old
uh what it is you want or your
grandmother or grandfather or whatever
like use many words as I tell my
children use your words uh in order to
explain something and uh it it certainly
makes a massive difference. Like if
you've seen any of the the workshops, a
lot of people use uh these markdown
files that are quite verbose and
describe in incredible detail what what
you want. And I find that is uh a way
better way to get the AI to do your
bidding. Um personally speaking anyway,
request.
So we give it
>> It's not my laptop. It's GitHub that's
broken. Is it? Is it? Seriously?
>> Oh my life.
>> Oh no, we've doeds GitHub.
>> Is that what it is?
>> It doesn't. Well, two two ways I guess.
You'll see.
H that's why when I did get push it
broke
>> in the dialog get a plus if it's
something obvious.
>> Oh man this light I can't get on. Do you
mind if I go dark?
>> Cannot get on with this.
>> There we go. Oh
>> things the way you want it to do. So
it's either not you'll either see it
because it's just not doing the thing
the ways for me
>> or you will actually see it like that.
It never reads it or never trying to
pull it.
>> Oh.
>> Uh well there's another way you can do
it. Uh you can uh in the repo if you go
to the top of the repo
>> you can download it
>> you can download it as a zip file and
probably
>> exactly and if you click on the
>> that will work
>> uh these are your workspaces. So if you
click on that there'll be nothing in
your private work but if yours
>> it does
>> if it's not import
>> so there's another option is download
the zip file unpack it
>> your personal one
>> and that might work
>> other repositories for your organization
for your team and then everyone in your
team are
>> 10 stars
>> Simon we've got 10 stars
>> as long as they're using the MTP server
that's installed
>> exactly next year um when when we what
we would do is we would we would add
something called a tessle JSON in your
directory and that then says These are
all the this is being built using this
knowledge.
>> So
>> I'll upload my example when GitHub comes
back
>> then pull all that knowledge into your
environment. It's a little bit like an
npm install
>> whereby you wouldn't check your your um
your your mpm
>> modules rather.
>> Um so it just pulls in that and then
every time it starts building it uses
that context. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Cool. No worries.
What are the chances that Cloudflare and
GitHub would go out in the same day?
>> It wouldn't surprise me if uh it's
because of Cloudflare that GitHub's
down. Perhaps
>> should all be in Azure, shouldn't it?
>> Yeah, possibly.
>> I guess roll the dice and guess which
one's going down tomorrow.
Sorry.
11 stars.
Sorry. Get excited with stars.
>> Just mine.
>> That's mine.
>> Oh, mine's here.
>> Has anyone done any like spec during
development before? Anyone like gone
into writing clear, very descriptive
specs? Do you find it like useful to
articulate, you know, or do you find it
just like a massive waste of time? What
did you try?
>> Bit of both.
>> Uh, yeah. I've I've just been trying to
see what I can do with with different
specs. So, I was trying to use like
Claude Flow the other day just to see if
I could max out everything and and how
fast I could put my AI slop together.
Uh, but then it ended up just that AI
slop even with a pretty good spec. I've
tried a few other things like Gustav and
a few other, you know, claude related
frameworks. I just started playing with
like Google ADK. I haven't tried your
guys' tools. Um, but so far I haven't
found a great way to like paralyze
everything and just be like generate
everything, yolo, and actually get a
good result.
>> Yeah, I Yeah, I'm not sure that's a good
go. That's a It's a great point. I'm not
sure like I I want to yolo my way to
success, but fun though it is. Um, I
think there's um there's something in
getting into that mindset where you're
articulating what you want really
explicitly
and using that as a blueprint for the
next time you're doing it. And that that
makes sense. You end up with a giant
spec that you're carrying around to each
project. But then
why keep that to myself? It's what I'm
thinking. I want to share that with the
world. I don't want it to be one giant
file. I want it to be broken down. I
want to have the little pieces. I want
atomic like that's the TypeScript bit.
That's the, you know, the the Python
back end. That's the database and have
all those little reusable components
that I can pick and choose from.
>> Yeah, I think the atomic bit makes a lot
of sense because the models, even if you
use a lesser model, they get really
distracted and if you don't give them
really small chunks, then they they can
easily go ary. So,
>> yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think uh like switching to um a
provider that has more tokens is really
like a coping strategy. Like like I I
switched to Gemini thinking, well, it's
okay cuz I can put more stuff in there,
which is just like it's like me going to
the kitchen trash and pushing it down
with my hands, right? At some point, I'm
going to have to take that outside,
right? [laughter]
I I can't just keep pushing it down,
right? Um, so yeah, that that's how I I
feel is I need to solve this problem
because it's getting a bit silly now.
>> Anyone else done any spec driven stuff
or articulating? Oh yeah. Wow. The
master of cursor rules over here.
>> Yeah. So I've done specdriven
development within cursor. So I've
created a custom mode in cursor um that
um takes specdriven development in
steps. So like step one is like getting
what I want out of my head so that the
agent understand what I want to develop
exactly. Then the second step is like
finding the relevant files and the
context from the system. So from the
actual code to understand that hey this
is the requirement now this is the code
then it actually the third step is
actually understanding the versions of
the libraries and kind of text and stuff
like that. So it discusses those things
with me and all of this is like really
collaborative. So it's like active
communication between me and cursor
figuring out what I want to do. The
fourth step would be like actually now
putting all of these things together to
to understand hey are there any missing
questions or issues or gaps that are
that that we need to fill before we
actually start implementing. It's going
to do that. The the fifth step would be
to actually define the test scenarios
and the acceptance criteria that we want
and how we would go about testing that
during the implementation phase itself.
The sixth phase will be like creating
the spec itself where we would create
everything in a spec. So I would take
that spec then and then create a new
thread in a new chat and then I would
just give that that you know uh spec and
then we'll basically start working on
that and this workflow for me has worked
extremely well wherein I'm able to like
oneshot whatever spec I create. Um but
it does take you know 30 minutes to an
hour just working on this spec itself
and then the development itself takes
like 10 to 15 minutes but
>> yeah that that's a very good point like
like [clears throat]
before I started looking at spectrum of
development I realized I was leveraging
other human meat bags to do this. Like I
would have an idea for an application
and I'd have a DM conversation with a
couple of friends and say, "Hey, what do
you think about this?" And have a
conversation and they would be almost
adversarial uh asking me questions.
Clarify this. What do you mean by that?
Cuz in my head, I know fully formed what
this application needs to look like and
I can visualize it. but trying to
explain it to another human. Um, I I
explained these applications to people
and sometimes I would end up nerd
sniping them and they would end up
writing it for me. Brilliant. Like
mission accomplished. But sometimes just
having that conversation, if I look back
over the conversation in DMs with this
person, I realize actually what they're
doing is clarifying everything. And some
of these things I hadn't thought of and
even like the viability of it as a as a
project or the already like prior art of
the existence of another tool that
already does the thing that I think I
had a I've had a shower thought this
thing should exist and it turns out it
already does. Somebody else did that.
Um, and I think that having that uh that
conversation with an AI or with another
human, it takes the load off my friends
and they get less annoyed, but also I
end up with a way that I can summarize
that thing. Like you're using an LLM to
summarize that and then take that to the
next part of the process. Is that like
you do with like the multi-step process?
I love that. It just fits my brain
somehow.
>> Got a question over here, Alan.
>> Uh, I can't see. Where are you?
>> I'm here. Um at the back. I'm waving
right now.
>> I can't see you. Where are you?
>> I'm here. I'm looking right at you.
>> Yeah, that's
>> You can't see me.
>> Oh, there you are. I need new glasses.
>> Go ahead.
>> Okay.
>> Here you go.
Okay. Um he was just joking with you.
We're over here on the left on your
right. Um, [laughter]
>> but uh, yeah, I wanted to comment about
that and like yeah, sometimes I feel
really lazy and like there are words for
what I want to describe and I would just
like the LM to guess until it guesses
them correctly and writes them down for
me and then once it looks like it's
close enough, then it can start working
on it. U, and then the babysitting
starts. But like having to think of
those words for like a codebase can be
really expensive or just exhausting. And
so just like give it to the LM, it'll
like draft it pretty well. Um, and like
you said, like there's a lot of I'm not
like a perfect engineer, right? Like I
don't know a lot of the words that may
be useful for the LM to implement it
correctly. So asking it to give me
suggestions like um the speaker said uh
don't limit it with like what you want
uh or what you can think of. It's just
like I have a vague idea what what can
you think of helps a lot.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. I I find like
the first thing in the morning, that
morning moment when you're like, I've
had like I've had a fever dream and I
know what I want and I've got to get it
out. That's the best time to have that
conversation, right? And get it get it
down on paper. I have so many of these
like ideas and they're all written down
and I've got these big specs and just
I've I've gone from having
uh not enough time to write the code to
not knowing which of these projects that
I can spend the next few hours like
actually turning into a real thing. That
it's not a bad problem to have really,
is it?
>> Yeah. I think as well for specs that are
reusable by lots of people, I think
there'll probably be an ownership switch
where it won't actually be developers
necessarily writing a lot of the
guidance. Uh it will probably be
platform teams that certainly own it. Uh
own the distribution and possibly kind
of probably workshop a lot of the text
with with various people from an app
point of view where you create apps that
are specs. Yeah, there's I think I feel
like there's a bit of a technology gap
there, which is one of the reasons why
we as Tesla are focusing more heavily on
the spec registry and the the idea of
guidance to agents and and how you
actually improve agents as best you can.
Um, but also, yeah, when we talk about
the oneshot kind of based on a spec, I I
think that's the future. There will be
there there is a vision that we're
working to certainly at Tesla where the
point is everything's written down
enough where you can oneshot it. But I
think that's not where we are right now
in terms of uh what the capabilities are
of an LLM. Um but uh but yeah, it's
would be interesting to see how a lot of
that's possibly taken up by a program by
a platform team certainly for guidance
and and best practices of development.
Okay. Who's uh where where are we? Who's
uh who's who's created a Tesla account
and
maybe a spec?
I'd love to know if anyone's got any
ideas like what like where what are you
going to data you going to introspect?
What are you going to rumage around in?
That would be awesome.
Let's get her back.
What was wrong with it? Oh wow.
>> Yeah, it it down.
>> Oh dear. Well, no more development
today.
Yeah. Try something.
Oh my gosh.
Um,
>> it
[snorts] Yeah, good point actually. Uh,
instead of a full fork,
>> you can download.
>> Ah, you can fork it and then download
the zip directly and then just unzip
that onto your
>> Yeah.
Yeah, at the bottom down it's up.
[snorts]
>> I just had a question.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
>> hi there. Just a quick question. I was
trying to understand fully what you guys
mean by specs. Are these like prompts?
like just really elaborate prompts that
are in a very particular
uh format and uh it's like a global
format. Is that what the specs are? And
and and that's what's helping with the
tiles. Is that I'm sorry for
>> Yeah,
>> trying to get a little clear on this.
>> It's a great question. like what is a
spec and like in my mind I see it as
like all the slides that that Simon
showed where uh uh an agent can kind of
deviate from the happy path that you
want to get to like you've got a goal I
want to create this web app or whatever
it might be and there's a happy path to
get there but the happy path is beset
with branches off in directions that are
not going to ultimately end up or they
might go via a very
securous route and there may be uh
incorrect assumptions made by the LLM
because you didn't articulate
specifically that you actually want this
version of Python or that particular
framework or I want all my tests to be
compliant with this company standard or
you whatever whatever those uh facts are
that it should have known up front that
we assume it knows in some cases those
being articulated ated in a
not necessarily even a universal way,
but a standardized way. And they all
open markdown files. And so yeah,
something which like in general a spec
generally has um the details that are
enough to try to guide the agent back on
the happy path. And that may mean
telling it specific tools you want to
use, specific frameworks, uh, versions
or, um, or other like compliance
guidelines based on what your rules are
within your organization. Um, now
different organizations have different
ideas about what they think that spec
format should look like, but in general
it's a human readable piece of text that
articulates
a part of the development process. Is
that fair?
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I think it's funny how
everyone uses markdown. Um, but I think
there's a couple of good reasons. one
because visually for humans it's
actually very nice to to look at and to
be able to section and and have nice
headers and things like that. Um, but
when we think about how LLMs consume
that as well, LLMs love the sections and
the titles and things like that, they
will actually when we when we did early
stage um testing on what how an LLM
consumes a spec, we we originally did a
bunch of stuff where we used almost like
an XML format of tags to say this is a
section start and end. And it was it it
when it consumed a a a spec that had
that level of categorization or
sectioning, it it produced far better
output. Um and and you'll find a lot of
vendors, a lot of people who are trying
to create a style of specification for
their tools use markdown not just
because it's neat neater to for a human
to read it, but they will get better
output from their LM as a result. Um
and I think
like there's no real standardization of
what a spec should look like. I mean,
it's all natural language and just just
descriptive trying to trying to capture
our intent or our um decisions that
we're trying to make. There's a lot that
you don't have to write in a spec if you
don't care about what how an LLM
actually makes that decision or or how
it will implement something from that.
You might want to provide that as
context to the LLM. if you reiterate
through your code creation just so your
output isn't wildly different version to
version. Um but but I think as was kind
of mentioned sometimes the the the less
you give an LLM sometimes the better
result as well because it can make a lot
of those decisions by itself. Uh but
yeah, I think it's the spec is really
capture of intent, which when we think
about a code to spec. Um it's it's very
hard in the code to spec process to
determine intent from code. Uh because
there's too much implementation noise in
there. Uh so so think of it as just a
set of intents that are that are built
in a that that are detailed in a way
whereby they're they're sectioned and an
LLM can you know understand your intent
and therefore using that context create
something in a in a more more
representable way to your to your needs.
Um yeah, I just had a question around
like what mitigation tactics if any
Tesla uses in terms of um avoiding
context bloat. So like how many tools
are available in the MCP and do you have
like checks and balances in there to
make sure that doesn't happen?
Yeah, it's a really good question and I
think as an as a project grows as well,
the amount of context can get massively
out of hand. And I think the the key is
oop sorry the key the key is there's a
um
there's a the MCP tool which is I think
it's called get library context or
something along those lines and what it
does is based on the based on the
request you make. So if I was to say
create create a new
let's say I have a usage spec for the
commander CLI library and I say create
this new addition to my CLI it will
spawn off a sub agent number one that
will effectively go if essentially do a
research style task and it will look
through all the context it has that is
relevant and pull just the amounts from
that into the contain
uh agent's context that it needs to
better
better perform that task. So it's not
actually pulling everything across and
even that research is happening on a
separate separate uh task as well. So
it's not actually using that context and
once it has that limited context that it
actually needs to pass in that's going
to be an amount that shouldn't blow your
context window. Uh there's obviously
we're we're a beta product right now so
we haven't tested it to the extreme and
there probably will be edge cases where
it's like oh crap we're way over or
whatever. Um but uh but yeah right now
it's sub agents and handling things off
the main agent which causes uh all the
bloat of of context to to avoid the main
agent.
Uh if you're using Claude, by the way, a
really useful uh command in Claude is to
type slash context and it'll were away
for a little bit and then it will show
you this really nice little kind of
histogram like Oh, here we go. Are you
going to do it?
>> Yeah. I was just trying to find one of
the many tabs that has my claw. Uh
>> that's a good question, Joe. Do we know
the token size for
>> uh for for our MCP?
Jay's a Jay's a developer on our team,
by the way. I'm not just asking random
stranger.
>> Uh I don't know about the MCP server
itself, but we pull in uh we pull in the
relevant context based on the request.
So we're not just throwing everything in
the system context window. So if you've
got a request about writing some tests
about something, it will pull out your
testing guidelines, say, but it's not
going to pull everything else into
context. Um so you're not blowing up
your context window, if that answers
your question. [snorts]
So is it is it does Tesla know how much
is left and does work to make sure it
doesn't blow that context window?
>> Is that the question? No, it was more
like for instance like uh
>> um you know early on when MCPS first
started like uh you know the context 7
moment or or even like playright and so
uh you know I started incorporating more
and more MCPs and binding those tools to
to my agents and then very quickly I
realized like I'm getting way worse
results from the LLM.
Um, and so like something like Playright
has 128 tools that it ships with. So if
like you just leave that on and you're
not paying attention, like that's
already eating up I think you know close
to like 50k tokens in in context just by
having it there. So that's why I was
curious. But um you clearly have the MCP
here and uh I don't know if you only
have Tesla MCP. If if that's the only
one, then you are kind of around 60k
tokens, which is quite a lot.
>> Yeah, if you look at my uh the nonsense
thing I made earlier, uh I have a few
tools, not just test. I've got a whole
bunch of other nonsense in there. And
you can see the MCB tools takes up by
far and away the majority of the
content. I'm obviously nowhere near the
end, but they take up quite a bit of
space.
>> If you if you scroll down to Tessle
>> Yeah. It's way down the bottom.
>> But I didn't actually use Tesla at all.
>> No. No. So, yeah. Only
>> few thousand. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Some of these are just enormous. I
would love to ask a follow-up question
because it feels like you're saying
you're doing some kind of lazy load with
MCP. Is that right? I thought they
didn't do that, but if you know how to
do that, I would love to know.
>> It's a good way of putting it. Um, yeah,
it's one MCP in MCP tool that's called
and we ask the agent to explain
essentially what the users asked to do.
Um, and then we use that to then search
through the knowledge and pull out the
relevant files. So it's a it's sort of a
way it's essentially a way of of doing a
lazy MCP uh call with one tool.
>> You just basically have a
>> So basically, if I understand you
correctly, you just have like one MCP
piece that knows all about your tools
and it doesn't pull everything else, but
it can search and pull it that that's
awesome. Thank you.
>> Yes. So the search and the search and
install will kind of pull all the
knowledge down. So you'll have
everything locally, but then the the the
the the context library will only pull
then those relevant pieces once it's
called and fill the context with not
fill it, but add to the context those
few pieces. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. Because we in in some of our
original tests, it was kind of we
realized quickly how it it it blew up
the context and so we needed that
research step. Um did you want to add?
>> Yeah, just maybe a helpful metaphor is
uh we sometimes think of it as like um
bit like npm. Um so you're running npm
install, you're pulling your
dependencies into a node modules folder.
You're not committing that but it's sort
of like part of your setup and then you
know you import the things that you
need. Um so it's maybe a helpful
metaphor to think about.
>> Awesome. So, um,
is if anyone's if anyone's created some
specs that they want to contribute, feel
free to put your hand up and I'll come
around and I'll share the or I'll grab
your username and add that to the to the
workspace. Um, would it be good for us
to maybe do a bit of live coding? Add uh
create create a um
>> yeah
a data source that's innocuous. I could
put commit to video
>> claude history.
>> Uh
yeah.
>> What's most personal about you, Alan,
that we can share on uh on a recorded?
>> Probably cat pictures. [laughter]
Uh oh, man.
Yeah,
put me off stage. Ask me that. Um,
yeah. Problem is I don't use most of
these tools. Um, like the the one main
one I use is Spotify. You know, GitHub
is a good one, but uh
>> Spotify.
>> Yeah, but Spotify exists and Spotify
wrapped exists. I'd like to like uh
>> how about a YouTube? Can I get
>> what videos I've watched? How much of my
life have I wasted watching YouTube?
Should we give that a go?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, my life. I am opening myself up
here. Uh like um let's put this in the
scratch folder.
Uh there's nothing there, right? Um I
haven't got any MCPS or anything, have
I? Uh
if I do tessle in it, right, we're going
to collaboratively work on
um right. So now
is this text big enough? Do you need it
bigger?
>> Is that all right? Okay, cool. Um
right, I'll use Claude.
Yep.
Okay,
[snorts]
I'd like to make my own Spotify rap
style
uh page, but for my own personal YouTube
watch history. Oh man,
I'm not even up to my three month like
probationary period. Um
okay. Uh
this will need two uh stages.
One to G data gather gather
data using
YouTube YouTube
API
and the can I get it from the YouTube
there to
>> I think it might be uh YouTube MCP maybe
>> uh web page to
show the data
in Baby
or way if you like
bra
start
uh right what are we going to need?
Uh any do we want to specify any
particular libraries or tools or
frameworks? Shout them out and they will
get integrated if you're not careful.
language.
>> Oh, pick a language. Backend Python,
front end node, something else. Backend
Rust. Let's go. Oh god, there's always
one. Um, okay. Well, why not? Well, no,
because we'll spend all the time
building it.
>> Sorry.
>> Python sounds great. Let's use Python.
Python for the back end.
Hey,
>> yeah, we use UV. Yeah, UV is the best.
Uh, and UV for the package management
dependency management.
[snorts]
We are not currently in a UV
environment.
We'll need to make that
>> [snorts]
>> I'm not usually this for both uh front
uh anything else any other uh it it
should be able to figure out
uh looking
in the Tesla registry for Python modules
specs that we can use on the back end.
>> Good shout. Uh what about the front end?
What do we want? node I suppose
>> uh node for the front end
any particular like like do we want to
use react or something else something
lean
>> do react
>> react not react hey how about react
for the framework.
By the way, I should have introduced
this whole thing with I'm not a
developer. I mean, that clearly shows,
right? You know this. Okay, good.
[laughter] Uh,
forgot framework again. Look in the
Tessle registry
specs that can help us.
Uh, what else do we need? test framework
tests
are for losers. So, we'll do that
another day.
Yeah, I'm I'm kidding. Uh are for
people
who have more than 44 minutes left on
the clock.
[snorts] So, we'll do that another day.
Uh, anything else?
Uh, the UI. What should the UI look
like? I have mentioned brain rot,
haven't I? Oh dear. Um,
should we see how it goes with that?
Build build me first.
First build me a spec
detailed spec and to-do list
for this project. This is terrible. Like
ordinarily I would have a whole load of
uh um MCPS and loads of other stuff
added. So this is going in very raw for
me. Anything else we need to add? Shout
now or I'll press enter.
>> Do it.
At some point I'm going to have to go
and get a YouTube API key, aren't I?
Right. I'm gonna say yolo do everything
fast API. Oh, look at that. Found a
YouTube transcript API. That's not quite
what I want, but okay.
React animations.
Perfect, says [laughter] Claude. Let's
create a comprehensive spect. Okay.
Now, obviously, we could have used any
tool. I just happen to have Claude open
in this terminal at the time. We could
have used VS Code or uh Copilot or
whatever. [snorts]
Is there a preference? Does everyone
just use everything or is there Claude?
Everyone Claude or Gemini or Gemini?
Gemini. Gemini. GVT.
Wow. Does nobody use Open AI anymore?
Remember them. Okay. Where is the
structure? Two clear stages. Do it. Um,
has it written anything yet?
>> No. Okay.
Do it.
Uh, hang on. Displaying in an
over-the-top meme style wrapped
experience. Oh, good.
Brilliant. Uh,
yes. And always create stuff.
I worry this is going to go wrong.
Whose YouTube account do I have access
to that's not mine?
Right. So, it's using it's understood
it's using UV. Good. Just do it. I would
never use UV in it. That's interesting.
Interesting [snorts] that chose Python
311.
Where's uh Joe? Simon, is this what you
expect?
Pi Pi Google API Python client
do it.
>> We're yoloing this project. It's 41
minutes in counting.
Okay.
Law.
There's a command line option for claw,
isn't there, that makes it into yolo
mode, or is it like accept all?
>> Oh, a tile has been added to your
project's test.json and extracted. Ah,
there we go.
Uh, okay. Has it just not saved that
yet? Was I too premature?
YouTube API fetch a script to retrieve
history. Okay.
Wow. What did we get? We got We got some
Python
extracted to there. I wonder where that
went.
No, there was nothing in there, I don't
think.
>> Oh, hang on. Is it in the back end? Uh,
yeah. Let's put it all down here.
No, maybe in source.
No. Where's he put it?
>> Oh, there you go. Look. Back end tessle
tiles. There we go. Nice.
Okay.
So, this is
>> steering for Tesla.
>> Nice.
Okay. Interesting. It says you're
working in a large organization.
[clears throat]
>> Yes. Uh,
that looks like a yolo. [snorts]
>> You're going to make me run this, aren't
you?
>> I was curious what you watch.
>> What? Front end. Bold front end temp
front end. It's like I think it's got
itself a little bit confused.
What have we got in there?
Oh, I don't want to do tree, do I? Uh,
yeah. Front end.
>> Wonder what went wrong with that.
>> Anyone see what went wrong with it?
Python back end and then when it started
on the front end
force.
>> Wow.
Let me try a different oper operate. So
it just killed that and started again.
Okay, [snorts]
fair enough. I should just not question
this and uh yeah having a nodding bird
on my enter key. I was I forgot to
>> What?
Claude, come on.
>> Okay.
Have any of you ever done uh vibe coding
while someone's watching?
I've watched people on YouTube do it and
uh
>> yeah,
>> maybe that'll show up in my uh in my
list.
>> A tile has been added to your project.
Okay.
>> Yeah, let's just do it.
>> [snorts]
>> You know, one day AI is going to see
that line and it's going to connect to
my bank account and just like send money
to these projects. That's Hey, someone
should make an MCP that does that. It's
like, oh well, you're clearly using it.
You should contribute.
>> Oh my gosh. Creating brain rock style
animated components for stats reveal.
Good lord,
>> this better be worth it.
>> Would it be all right if I said create
sample data for this rather than using
[snorts]
Now,
>> do you do something else while you're
doing this? Do you ever like watch TV or
like have a film on? Yeah, watch two
TVs.
>> Oh, two other projects. Oh, of course.
Yeah. Yeah. Just have it all going in
parallel. Of course.
>> Yeah.
>> [snorts]
>> I've um Have I got audio on? Yeah.
>> Oh, have I got it? Yeah,
>> I have um a hook in. Have I got it on
this one?
Yeah. So, I have it like a hook
>> when um
if I get distracted by the TV or while
I'm cooking or looking after the
children, um I have it say out loud,
"God is waiting for human response."
uh then I know the laptop needs me and I
have to drop the children and uh get
back to the computer.
>> It's quite useful.
The really weird thing is this.
>> You can actually have uh there's a bunch
of voices and a a speech synthesis
synthesis
uh called Piper. And if you want down
here in English
GB is my voice. Um, [snorts] so this
>> if you really wanted, you could have
Claude talk to you in my voice.
>> Yeah, you probably don't want to do
that.
>> Okay, still going.
>> But yeah, sorry.
Hope you didn't hear my snoring.
>> Come on. You got 33 minutes left.
>> Well, he thinks it's done.
There's no way
to
speed.
>> Claude is waiting for human response
>> like that.
>> No way.
>> Okay.
>> Little
>> is there sample data in here?
>> Oh, to configure to use mock data.
Okay, let's see.
>> Is that working?
>> Okay, let's go.
Do we really want to click on this?
>> Press the wrong button,
>> right? This better be good.
>> What do we think?
>> [laughter]
>> thing.
>> Oh, dear me.
Is it running on 8,000? Where's the
>> You're running the
>> back end. Uh
>> well, it is, isn't it?
>> That's a good question.
Is it because it's not a networking
thing because this is on
>> an error
>> local host and the other one is on
>> 127001
>> or is it 127
>> local
>> suggestions welcome
>> I mean I could
>> that's the right way to do it. Expose it
to the world. This production code.
>> Oh no. This is not the one that needs
exposing, is it?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Go for it. I I will take any
suggestions.
>> Launch both of these. Yeah.
Uh, where did it cool? There he is. Hang
on.
>> He's already confused. He's
>> dramatic animations.
>> Yeah, people always put this last
So I'm saying give me a shell script
that launches it and then run that. Make
sure it works and there are no errors
between the front and the back end.
Oh, and
run it on 00 Z00 Z for funsies.
>> H.
>> Yeah, both of them can be on 00 but
but different ports. I assume it knows
that, doesn't it? Claude's not that daft
surely.
Right. While that's happening, come on.
>> Can I just like use this time to mention
something else that I vibe coded?
>> Go here and find nerdy places to go all
around the world. Uh uh and uh there are
already quite a lot in America. And if
you find any other nerdy places to go,
can you please add them to this website?
This was almost 100% vibe coded up the
wazoo and there's a lot of places here
but uh yeah if you could add places to
nerdy daytrips.org just a little side
project. Uh that'll be awesome. Thanks
very much.
>> Uh [groaning]
what's that?
What is that?
Oh my gosh. I don't even know what that
is. This one doesn't have a description.
There's also it's all in GitHub. You can
do pull requests to fix that.
>> [snorts]
>> Um, I think Claude's still working. No,
it's finished.
We'll come back to that if we have time.
But yeah, uh, I'm sure there's there's
stuff here somewhere. Is that Long
Island? It is, isn't it? Oh, look. Look
at that. Some of them have stuff. Uh,
anyway, let's go back to what we're
actually here for. Um,
>> so, okay.
>> Yeah, just do it.
[snorts]
So, so what's [snorts]
>> 8,000? I know. It's got loads of
different ports to roll.
>> Why is it obsessed with putting emojis
in literally everything?
>> Like there's a shell script. Fill it
with emojis.
>> Yes, just curl is fine. Do it. [snorts]
Yes.
>> So, it's launched something in the
background.
This is very much don't do it like this.
>> Do we think that's up now?
>> Claude is waiting for human response.
>> Thanks.
Okay,
it's still running by the look of it.
Did it just kill it while I was about to
load it or did something No.
Is that all it does?
Literally, that's all it does. Wow.
Super disappointed.
I mean, if it could do the rest of it
like that, that would be amazing. But
there is I think there's nothing in
there. Oh, man.
>> The other thing you could do is if you
wanted to wanted it to
>> after all of that
>> I mean all of that all I did was press
enter a lot um
>> uh I wonder
So, [snorts] there's a problem here.
>> Uh, have I got any extensions that are
causing this to go? No.
[snorts]
>> Can someone please help?
>> I got this.
>> Oh, my life.
>> [snorts]
>> I think we may
have
being too hasty.
Testing was probably a good idea
because
I get a great splash screen.
Then the world goes black
and I get an error
the console
right while that's working. Uh
any other nerdy day trips? Uh
>> South Dakota. [snorts]
>> South Dakota. I I don't I'm not
American. I don't know where those those
are. Where's South Dakota go? Left a
bit, right a bit?
>> It's like here somewhere, is it?
>> That's Albuquerque.
>> That's not it, is it? There's not a lot
around this kind of area, is there?
>> Yeah, that's just like [snorts] a
general statement of fact. Yeah.
Come on.
However, you can add your own. If you if
you know someone, add it, please.
Oh, I I tell you what I didn't show you.
The best part of this whole website,
right, is my note Stewart added a thing
that lets you go.
[laughter]
This is the only reason this exists is
just donk.
That's so cool. Uh, right. This is still
going. Fixing
Is that literally all it does?
Ah, classic.
Is this true?
>> Is that true?
Okay, I'll allow it.
This is
Is it? It says f it. That's what it's
doing.
What's it doing? It's not doing
anything.
[snorts]
Oh, it is.
It's just taking its time. Right. Back
to nerdy day trips.
Uh, did you know there's a pencil
museum? I think there's more than one as
well.
Look at that. Derwent Pencil Museum.
If you want to go to Derwent, you can go
to the pencil museum. Come on. Come on.
Come on. [snorts]
Is it actually doing anything?
Oh my life.
>> Okay.
[snorts]
Okay. So, with the sample data, it
appears to have made a thing that
uh I'm not sure this is brain rot
enough, but uh it's um
made with a skull and questionable life
choices. Is that all it does? Literally.
Oh,
[snorts] some videos watched. Right. All
right. Oh,
now come on.
I mean, it's done something like
See, this is what I was after. The
animations.
Okay. Yeah, it worked.
Is
No, I'm not connecting it to mine.
That is quite cool. Uh, Simon, it
worked. Uh, our job is done. Like,
[snorts]
no, it's sample data. It's not my It's
not my YouTube account. Uh, and um yeah,
I'm not doing that until like ask me
tomorrow. I'll do it on my laptop. I'm
not doing it on a projector. I love
[snorts] this.
>> I mean, it's all plausibly true,
[laughter]
but you know.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, true.
>> Yeah,
it worked.
[snorts] Uh, if anyone has any
questions, for sure.
>> Oh, have you not got your um No, you to
ask the gentleman over there. They're
bus they're busy adding things to Nerdy
Day trips.
What do we get?
>> Test, test, test. There you go. Any any
questions
[snorts] about anything that we've
covered? Oh, one question.
>> Okay, there is your tile.
>> Did it generate these or did it get
these from the registry?
Right.
>> Yep.
[snorts]
>> You're right. Except Right.
If you um fade out my laptop, I will go
and register and get an API key because
you know what could possibly go wrong.
>> For the hardcore people who stayed here,
>> let's just do this.
Um, could you like hide my laptop and
put something else up?
>> Thank you.
>> I'm going to regret this, aren't I?
>> [snorts]
[snorts]
>> Right. Sign in to Google.
>> Good.
>> Uh,
create a new project or select an
existing one.
And then when you come back,
>> what I ended up what I ended up doing
New project
>> YouTube
>> frame rock.
APIs and services.
>> What's it called? YouTube a data API v3.
API v3.
enable.
[snorts]
Okay.
Uh create an O2 credentials.
Really do I have to do this credentials?
Create credential.
Oorth client ID.
>> You must first have a consent screen.
App name YouTube brain rock
>> support email address
audience this is internal use only
contact information
my email address
next I agree to all of the data policies
create an orth client as a desktop app.
I'm just like clicking through. Name
YouTube brain.
Create.
Oh my gosh. Right.
Okay. I've got a credentials.json.
Put the credentials JSON in the backend
directory.
Okay.
[snorts]
>> Um
Oh my god.
Give me
[snorts]
right
done.
How do I kill this and launch it again?
[snorts]
Let me just kill the other one.
Right.
>> Let's say you have a spec.
>> I had a launch program here somewhere,
didn't I?
very like day in day out that kind of
>> we don't think it can do that.
>> How can this possibly work?
>> We think it will [clears throat] be able
to in future and that's what that's the
vision we have
>> kind of going in that direction.
But the area that we feel
most kind of
urgently needed is guidance and support
to be able to be able to develop almost
rails.
>> Uh so
>> I got the credentials file and I plopped
it in the back end. I I'm not going to
show it to you just yet. I've just told
Claude that it doesn't seem to be using
it.
>> Uh oh.
>> Oh god. Open the Gmail app on my phone.
Oh, my phone is in airplane mode.
>> Oh my god. It's actually doing it.
>> God.
[snorts]
Bear with me just one moment. I have to
authenticate this nonsense.
>> Here we go. Yes.
YouTube brain wants to access your
Google account. Allow
[snorts] the authentication flow has
completed.
>> Claude is waiting for human response.
>> All right. All right. Calm down.
>> After that, it'll fetch.
>> Oh my god.
Right,
let's relaunch the thing.
>> Waiting for back ends to initialize.
[snorts]
>> This is so exciting.
>> [snorts]
>> Okay. I [snorts] told Claude it's
authorized, but it's still showing uh
mocked data. So,
you may be able to show my display now.
>> Oh god.
Uh, okay. It's made a change.
>> Uh, do you want to flip the thing to
show my display?
>> Oh god. Yeah, it really has got my data.
Oh crap. Um,
>> waiting for human response.
>> Could you um switch to show my There we
go.
>> Uh,
wow. Okay. So,
here we go. Is it going to work? Oh,
man. Right. Well, it's I'm still
unhinged, apparently.
>> Oh, well, that's not what it was. My
previous employer,
>> comedy news, a lawyer, internet today,
and uh a lefty YouTuber. [laughter]
This is why I was worried about doing
this. Uh, okay. Okay. Most active hour,
8:00 at night. Good. Active day, Friday.
Un unsurprising. It needs to pause a bit
longer on this, doesn't it?
Right. Well, it worked. And it wasn't as
scary as I thought it was going to be.
[applause]
[laughter] Top 92% of YouTube addicts.
Check me out. Oh my gosh. Have a Yeah, I
like that.
Good lord. Couple of months. No
judgment. Maybe a little bit of
judgment.
>> Watch street 26 days. What? Longest
binge 6.3 hours.
I don't know what we've learned here,
but uh it works. And um
never doing that again.
Any questions?
[snorts] Oh my life. You're saying
no.
Uh, Simon,
>> great success. This is my YouTube data.
>> I'll never be let back in the uh in the
US.
[laughter]
[sighs]
>> 9 hours.
>> Hey, it's good. I seriously watch
YouTube for 9 hours.
>> I think I must. Yeah, it worked.
>> Yeah,
>> this is my actual YouTube data. I'm
quite amazed.
>> Apparently, at some point I watched
YouTube for 9 hours solid.
>> Yeah, maybe I fell asleep in front of
the in front of the laptop.
Wow.
>> Okay. Awesome. Um,
>> everyone coming here tomorrow?
>> I do hope so.
>> Awesome. Awesome. There is a a deeper
dive into Tessle with uh Drew who's our
head of products. Uh, and that's
happening at uh time [snorts]
>> uh tools and action 4 p.m. I think going
by memory or 410ish. Um,
if we scroll,
>> day two.
>> Yep. All the way to the bottom. Pretty
much I think it's the penultimate uh
session before the keynotes.
>> Uh, search for Drew.
>> There he is.
>> Uh, so 4 p.m. 4 p.m. Yeah. In the
landing lower level. So other side
ground uh the the lower floor uh he's
going to be he's going to be talking
about uh a little bit deeper into Tessle
doing some demos and things like that
deeper than I did. We also have GIO
who's the founder and creator of Tessle
who's giving the keynote tomorrow
morning first thing. Uh so uh so we can
you can go more into more depth and hear
about more about the vision uh from from
GIO himself.
>> And I'm pretty sure neither Drew or Gipo
are going to share their YouTube
history.
>> Almost certainly not. Almost certainly
not. It's definitely going to be better
than this.
>> Awesome. Thank you very much uh for
attending and uh we'll see you tomorrow
as well. Thank you.
>> Thanks everyone. [music]
>> [music]